Guide to the Robert Wilson papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series II
  - Subseries II.9: Miscellaneous Contracts
    - Miscellaneous Contracts -- BHF APPROVAL NECESSARY -- --A.CIVIL warS contracts-- Raymond Louis, Jean Paul Rey -- --B.CIVIL warS, contract negotiations with A.R.T., 1984 -- --C.CIVIL warS Japan, contracts -- --D.CIVIL warS Koln, Wilson - Glass agreement -- --E.CIVIL warS Koln, contracts -- --F.CIVIL warS Koln, grand rights agreement -- --G.CIVIL warS Koln, Wilson - Glass grand rights agreement -- --H.CIVIL warS Koln, Wilson - Muller grand rights agreement -- -- -- --I.CIVIL warS Koln, broadcast agreement -- --J.CIVIL warS A.R.T. agreement -- --K.CIVIL warS A.R.T. agreement with Muller -- --L.CIVIL warS A.R.T. contract accounting -- --M.CIVIL warS Texas 1986, contract negotiations -- --N.CIVIL warS Texas 1986, French section -- --O.CIVIL warS Texas 1986, agreement with Muller -- --P.CIVIL warS Texas 1986, agreement with Michaell O'Rand -- --Q.CIVIL warS Texas 1986, signed contracts -- --R.CIVIL warS, agreement with Beverly Emmons -- --S.CIVIL warS, French negotiations -- --T.CIVIL warS/ Knee Plays, Walker Arts Center contracts -- --U.Letter from Daniel Stern-- BHF approval necessary, [v.p.], 1984-1986 (Box 255, Folder 6)
- Series III
  - Subseries III.1: Chrolological Correspondence
    - Chrono correspondence, [v.p.], July 1988 - September 15, 1988 (Box 256)
    - Chrono correspondence, [v.p.], September 16, 1988 - November 30, 1988 (Box 257)
    - Chrono correspondence, [v.p.], December, 1988 - March, 1989 (Box 258)
    - Chrono correspondence, [v.p.], April, 1989 - June 15, 1989 (Box 259)
    - Chrono correspondence, [v.p.], June 16, 1989 - September, 1989 (Box 260)
    - Chrono correspondence, [v.p.], October, 1989 - December, 1989 (Box 261)
    - Chrono correspondence, [v.p.], January, 1990 - March, 1990 (Box 262)
    - Chrono correspondence, [v.p.], April, 1990 - May, 1990 (Box 263)
    - Chrono correspondence, [v.p.], June, 1990 - July 31, 1990 (Box 264)
    - Chrono correspondence, [v.p.], August, 1990 - October 15, 1990 (Box 265)
    - Chrono correspondence, [v.p.], October 16, 1990 - December 31, 1990 (Box 266)
    - Chrono correspondence, [v.p.], January, 1991 - March 15, 1991 (Box 267)
    - Chrono correspondence, [v.p.], March 16, 1991 - May, 1991 (Box 268)
    - Chrono correspondence, [v.p.], June, 1991 - August 15, 1991 (Box 269)
    - Chrono correspondence, [v.p.], August 16, 1991 - October, 20, 1991 (Box 270)
    - Chrono correspondence, [v.p.], October 21, 1991 - November 20, 1991 (Box 271)
    - Chrono correspondence, [v.p.], November 21, 1991 - December 31, 1991 (Box 272)
  - Subseries III.2: Faxes
    - Faxes from Robert Wilson, [v.p.], December, 1988 - September, 1991 (Box 273)
    - Faxes to Robert Wilson, [v.p.], May, 1991 - December 1991 (Box 274)
  - Subseries III.3: Financial
    - Financial Year 1984-85: -- --A.BHF Payroll Account Statements -- --B.BHF Restricted Account Statements -- --C.BHF Savings Account Chem Bank -- --D.BHF Payroll Account Deposits -- --E.Invoices -- --F.Accounts Paid - Micro Masters -- --G.BHF German DM Account/Deutsche Bank -- --H.French Franc Account Statements -- --I.BHF French Francs Account -- --J.Invoices -- --K.Airline tickets - used/Accounts Paid --, [v.p.], 1984-1985 (Box 275)
    - Financial Year 1984-85 -- --A.Accounts Payable folder - checkbook stubs and statements -- --B.BHF OPS Deposits -- --C.Fundraising - Deposits/BHF restricted -- --D.Fundraising - Deposits - Fees and Grants/BHF restricted -- --E.Deposits -- --F.Deposits -- --G.Deposits - BHF OPS: October, 1984 - November, 1984 -- --H.Deposits - BHF OPS: July, 1984 - September, 1984 -- --I.The Civil WarS Payrolll Account Statements -- --J.The Civil WarS OPS Account Statements, [v.p.], 1984/1985 (Box 276)
    - Financial Records - Civil WarS/French Production 1983-84 -- --A.General production expenses in Paris -- --B. Invoices for construction of sets in Paris -- --C. Cash expenses on tour -- --D. Accounting Books of French tour sent by B. Pesle, [v.p.], 1983/1984 (Box 277)
    - Paid Bills "A" - "C", [v.p.], Financial Year 1984 - 1985 (Box 278)
    - Paid Bills "D" - "L", [v.p.], Financial Year 1984 - 1985 (Box 279)
    - Paid Bills "M"- "R", [n.p.], Financial Year 1984 - 1985 (Box 280)
    - Financial Year 1984-1985: Paid Bills "S"-"Z" (Box 281)
    - Computer generated reports, [n.p.], Financial Year 1984 - 1985 (Box 282)
  - Subseries III.4: Programs and Presses
    - Assorted Programs and Press: -- --A. Die Zauberflote, Press, Opera Bastille, Paris, June 1991 -- --B. Mr. Bojangles Memory, Revue De Presse, Pompidou Centre, Paris, November 1991 -- --C. Mr. Bojangles Memory Catalogue, Pompidou Centre, Paris, November 1991 -- --D. Malady of Death Program, Schaubuhne Theater, Berlin, December 1991 -- --E. Monuments, Kestner Gesellschaft Hannover Exhibition, Press, January 1992 -- --F. Monuments, Kestner Gesellschaft Hanover Exhibition Catalogue, January 1992 -- --G. Parsifal Program, Houston Grand Opera, February, 1992 -- --H. Doctor Faustus Lights the Lights Program, Hebbel Theater, Berlin, April 1992 -- --I. Der Hamburger Parsifa: Eine Provokation? Hamburg Opera, 1992 -- --J. Theatre/Public, Robert Wilson, July-August 1992 -- --K. Einstein on the Beach Libretto, 1992 -- --L. Robert Wilson IVAM Exhibition Catalogue, Valencia, September 1992 -- --M.Danton's Death Program, Alley Theater, Houston, October 1992 -- --N. Convidados De Piedra Catalogue, Circulo Bellas Artes, Madrid, November 1992 -- --O.Einstein on the Beach Program, Festival D'Automne, Paris, December 1992 -- --P.Manner Vogue, December 1992, [v.p.], 1991/1992 (Box 283)
  - Subseries III.5: Projects
    - Cosmopolitan Greetings Projects
      - A.Cosmopolitan Greetings, Hamburg, 1988 (Box 284)
      - B.Cosmopolitan Greetings, Hamburg, 1988
      - C.Cosmopolitan Greetings, Hamburg, 1988
      - D.Cosmopolitan Greetings, Tour, [n.p.], 1988 - 1989
      - E.Cosmopolitan Greetings, Japan, 1990
      - A.Delphi Festival, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 285)
      - B.Denkraum Exhibition, [n.p.], 1989
      - C.Dittrich Opera, Poesien, 1989
      - D.Elephant, Paris, 1989
      - E.The Forest: -- --1. Contact Sheet -- --2. Correspondence -- --3. Archival Materials Checklist -- --4. Telefaxes -- --5 Rehearsal and Performance Schedule, BAM, 1988
      - F.The Forest, Barcelona, Automn Festival: -- --1. Proposal -- --2. Rehearsal and Performance -- --3. Synopsis/Product Book, November - December 1987 -- --4. Archival Materials -- Checklist -- --5. Faxes -- --6. Telexes, Barcelona, 1987
      - The Forest: -- --1. Freie Volksbuehne Theater -- --2. Berlin -- 1988/Darryl Pickney Text -- --3. Correspondence with David -- Byrne -- --4. Berlin 1988 - Workman's Compensation Form -- --5. The Epic of Gilgamesh and Engidu -- --6. Correspondence, Berlin, 1988 (Box 286)
      - B.The Forest - Berlin 1988: -- --1. Act VII Speech by K. -- Kertess -- --2. Heiner Muller/Essays -- --3. Costumes -- --4. RW Notes/Research -- --5. Cast and Crew, Berlin, 1988
      - C.The Forest - Film: -- 1. Berlin Senate Proposal -- 2.Berlin - European Cultural City 1988 -- 3. Research - Script -- 4. Research -- 5. Casting Notes by RW and David Byrne -- 6. Film Scenario/David Byrne -- 7. Telexes -- 8. Correspondence with David Byrne -- 9. Faxes 1988 -1989 -- 10. Preliminary Shooting Schedule -- 11. Story Option -- 12. Proposal -- 13. Correspondence, Berlin, [n.d.]
      - D.The Forest Tour: -- 1. Rehearsal/Performance Schedule -- 2. Telexes, [n.p.], [n.d.]
      - E. Golden Windows, University of Montreal, 1988 - 1989, Montreal, 1988
      - A. Japan, Seibu/Saison Tadasi, Yokoyama, 1986 (Box 287)
      - B.King Lear, Schauspiel Frankfurt, 1989: -- 1. Correspondence -- 2. Cast and Crew -- 3. Artworld/Intl. Television Series, 1990 -- 4. RW's Notes -- 5. RW's Notes -- 6. Frankfurt Research -- 7. Photos of Theater Space -- 8. Rehearsal and Performance Schedule -- 9. King Lear Exhibit - Suspended, 1989 -- 10. Synopsis of Scenes -- 11. German Television Documentary -- 12. Archival Material Checklist -- 13. Costume Studies, Frankfurt, 1989
      - A.Drafts of Text, Frankfurt, 1990 (Box 288)
      - B.Kunsthalle, 1989: -- --1. Dusseldorf Correspondence, 1989; -- --2. Kunsthalle, 1989, [v.p.], 1989
      - C.Video - IMATCO/ATANOR, [n.p.], 1989
      - D.William Carlos Williams Release, [n.p.], [n.d.]
      - E.Ages of Man Release, [n.p.], [n.d.]
      - A.Leverkuessen Museum Exhibition, Germany, 1989 (Box 289)
      - B.London, [n.d.]
      - C.Los Angeles, West Coast Gateway, 1988
      - D.Luna Park Satellite Broadcast, 1987
      - E.De Matere - Netherlands Opera, 1989: -- 1. Telexes -- 2. Cast and Crew -- 3. Correspondence with Louis Andriessen -- 4. Tickets -- 5. Archival Material -- 6. Rehearsal and Performance Schedule -- 7. Amsterdam - Script, 1988 -- 8. Faxes -- 9. Correspondence, Netherlands, 1989
      - A.De Materie, Netherlands Opera -- 1. Research -- 2. Program Text -- 3. Text and Synopsis (English and -- Dutch) -- 4. RW Drawings, Notes, and Sketches, Netherlands, 1989 (Box 290)
      - B.Medea Master, Opera de Lyon: -- 1. Correspondence -- 2. Video Documentation -- 3. Master File Text - Heiner -- Muller Contributor -- 4. Medea Master Precis, [n.p.], [n.d.]
      - C.Heiner Muller 60th Birthday, [n.p.], January 1989
      - D.Heiner Muller - Wolokholamsk Highway, [n.p.], [n.d.]
      - E.St. Sebastian: -- 1. Film, 1988 -- 2. Metropolitan Opera -- * Tickets -- 3. Metropolitan Opera - Opening Night Party -- 4. Paris Opera - Ballet by Debussy/Correspondence, 1988 -- 5. Paris Opera - Cast and Crew -- 6. Paris Opera -- * Cast Replacements --, [v.p.], 1988
      - A.Paris Opera Notes, Paris, 1988 (Box 291)
      - B.Rehearsal Schedule, [n.p.], [n.d.]
      - C. Technical Information, [n.p.], [n.d.]
      - D.RW Notes, [n.p.], [n.d.]
      - E. Telexes, [n.p.], [n.d.]
      - F. Documentary Fim - Worms, [n.p.], [n.d.]
      - G. German Television, [n.p.], [n.d.]
      - H. Scenic Designs, [n.p.], [n.d.]
      - I. Lighting Plots by Xavier de Richemont, [n.p.], [n.d.]
      - J. Paris Invitations, Paris, [n.d.]
      - K. Set Designs by Xavier de Richemont, [n.p.], [n.d.]
      - A. Research, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 292)
      - B. Drawings by Stephanie Barba, [n.p.], [n.d.]
      - C.RW Sketches, [n.p.], [n.d.]
      - D.RW Sketches for Program, [n.p.], [n.d.]
      - E.RW Drawings, [n.p.], [n.d.]
      - F.RW Notes/Sketches, [n.p.], [n.d.]
      - G.RW Notes, [n.p.], [n.d.]
      - H. Production Materials, [n.p.], [n.d.]
      - I. Archival Material Checklist, [n.p.], [n.d.]
      - J. POB/Garnier Correspondence, Paris, [n.d.]
      - K. Telexes, [n.p.], [n.d.]
      - L. Faxes, [n.p.], [n.d.]
      - M. Ticket Requests, [n.p.], [n.d.]
  - Subseries III.6: Press, Publicity, Projects
    - A. Archival Checklist/Correspondence/RW Calendars, [n.p.], 1990 1992 (Box 293)
    - B. Press and Publicity - Cards and Invitations, [n.p.], [n.d.]
    - C. Press: -- 1. Paper by Jenny Dunker for Wilson Center -- Conference -- 2. Quotes from German Press Reviews of Doktor Faustus Lights the Lights -- 3. Stuff Magazine -- 4. Danton's Death - The Story -- 5. New York Times Magazine, November 1992 -- 6. Le Corps en Jeu, 1993; -- 7. Spectacle, 1993, [v.p.], 1993
    - D. Gallery Openings, Exhibits, Productions: -- 1. When -- We Dead Awaken Playbills, Cambridge, A.R.T. -- 2. RW's Vision - Gund Gallery -- 3. Zeit Magazin by RW, footnotes by Heiner Muller -- 4. Vis a Vis Magazine -- 5. Connoisseur Magazine -- 6. RW's Vision - MFA Boston, 1991 -- 7. Room Three Checklist (misc. exhibition), [v.p.], 1991
    - E. Black Rider - Programs/Press, [n.p.], [n.d.]
    - F. De Materie - Press, [n.p.], [n.d.]
    - G. Doktor Faustus - Press, [n.p.], [n.d.]
    - H. King Lear, Schauspiel, Frankfurt, 1990
      [with Marianne Hoppe as Lear]
    - I. Lohengrin - Press, Opera Now, [n.p.], October 1991
    - J .Magic Flute - Press, European Elan, [n.p.], July 1991
    - K. Mr. Bojangles - Invitation, [n.p.], [n.d.]
    - L. La Nuit D'Avant La Jour - French Revolution Research, [n.p.], [n.d.]
    - M.Orlando: -- --1. Press - Arts Section, New York Times, June 1990 -- --2. Program - Schaubuhneamlehniner Platz -- --3. Program - 22 Drawings, Berlin, 1989
    - N.Orlando - Scripts (German and English), [n.p.], [n.d.]
    - O.Parsifal: -- --1. Premiere Notice -- --2. Performance Schedule -- --3. Opera Review, February 1992 -- --4. Houston Chronicle, [v.p.], February 1992
    - P.Swan Song - Munchen, Kammarspiele, Scahuspielehaus, [n.p.], [n.d.]
    - Q. Pratt Institute Commencement Program, [n.p.], [n.d.]
  - Subseries III.7: Additions
    - Valiente, Pedo Proceso de creacion de la obra de Robert Wilson [segunda parte], Universidad Complutense de Madrid, 2000, (1 volume, 296 pages, ) (Box 294)